<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="After_prayer_array">
        <item>Dua After prayer 1</item>
        <item>اللهُ أَكْبَرُ</item>
        <item>Allah-hu Akbar</item>
        <item>Allah is the greatest</item>
        <item>Ibn Abbas (R.A) said, we used to know that Allah\'s messenger had finished his prayer when we heard “Allahu Akbar”.
[Sahih Muslim vol. 1, 1209/1210, Bukhari Vol.1 Book 12/802] Al-Bhukari, Muslim 3/1685 At Trimidi 2/1038 &amp; Ahmed 5/218</item>
        <item>Recite ONCE Immediately after Tasleem</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 2</item>
        <item>أَسْتَغْفِرُ اللهَ</item>
        <item>Astaghfirullaaha</item>
        <item>I seek the forgiveness of Allah</item>
        <item>Sahih Muslim 1/414</item>
        <item>Recite THREE times after every Fard Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 3</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ أَنْتَ السَّلَامُ وَمِنْكَ السَّلَامُ، تَبَارَكْتَ يَا ذَا الْجَلَالِ وَالْإِكْرَامِ</item>
        <item>Alla\'humma antas salaam wa min kas salaam taba rakta ya dhal ja laa li wal ik raam
</item>
        <item>O\' Allah, You are the Peace, and You are the Source of Peace, You are Blessed, Oh Possessor of Glory and Honor</item>
        <item>On the authority of Aisha (R.A) it is reported that whenever the Messenger of Allah (S.A.W) made the Taslim, he would recite (this Dua).
[Abu Dawud no. 1512 and An-Nasa’i no. 1339]  Abu Dawud 2:62, Ibn Majah 2:1267,At-Trimidhi 5:515,Ahmed 5:360</item>
        <item>Recite ONCE after every Fard Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 4</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ أَعِنِّي عَلَى ذِكْرِكَ، وَشُكْرِكَ، وَحُسْنِ عِبَادَتِكَ</item>
        <item>Allahumma a\'inni ala dhikrika wa shukrika wa husni ibadatika
</item>
        <item>O Allah, help me remember You, to be grateful to You, and to worship You in an excellent manner</item>
        <item>One day the Prophet (S.A.W) took Mu’adh Ibn Jabal (R.A) by the hand and said ‘O Mu’adh, by Allah I love you, and I advise you, O Mu’adh, never forget to recite (this Du’a), after every prayer (Fard).[Abu Dawud, Book 16, Hadith 1422]</item>
        <item>Recite ONCE after every Fard Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 5</item>
        <item>لَا إِلٰهَ إِلَّا اللهُ وَحْدَهُ لَا شَرِيكَ لَهُ، لَهُ الْمُلْكُ وَلَهُ الْحَمْدُ وَهُوَ عَلَى كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ، لَا حَوْلَ وَلَا قُوَّةَ إِلَّا بِاللهِ، لَا إِلٰهَ إِلَّا اللهُ، وَلَا نَعْبُدُ إِلَّا إِيَّاهُ، لَه النِّعْمَةُ وَلَهُ الْفَضْلُ وَلَهُ الثَّنَاءُ الْحَسَنُ، لَا إِلٰهَ إِلَّا اللهُ مُخْلِصِينَ لَهُ الدِّينَ وَلَوْ كَرِهَ الْكَافِرُونَ</item>
        <item>Laa \'ilaaha \'illallaahu wahdahu laa shareeka lahu, lahul-mulku, wa lahul-hamdu wa Huwa \'alaa kulli shay \'in Qadeer. Laa hawla wa laa quwwata \'illaa billaahi, laa \'ilaaha \'illallaahu, wa laa na\'budu \'illaa \'iyyaahu, lahun-ni\'matu wa lahul-fadhlu wa lahuth-thanaa\'ul-hasanu, laa \'ilaaha \'illallaahu mukhliseena lahud-deena wa law karihal-kaafiroon</item>
        <item>None has the right to be worshipped but Allah alone, He has no partner, His is the dominion and His is the praise and He is Able to do all things. There is no power and no might except by Allah . None has the right to be worshipped but Allah, and we do not worship any other besides Him . His is grace , and His is bounty and to Him belongs the most excellent praise. None has the right to be worshipped but Allah . (We are) sincere in making our religious devotion to Him, even though the disbelievers may dislike it.</item>
        <item>On the authority of \'Abdullah bin Az-Zubair (R.A) the Prophet (S.A.W) used to say at the end of the prayer, after making the Taslim. [Muslim no. 594] Muslim 1/415
 </item>
        <item>Recite ONCE after every Fard Salah
</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 6</item>
        <item>سُبْحَانَ اللهِ
        الْحَمْدُ للهِ
        اللهُ أَكْبَرُ
        ا إِلٰهَ إِلَّا اللهُ وَحْدَهُ لَا شَرِيكَ لَهُ، لَهُ الْمُلْكُ وَلَهُ الْحَمْدُ وَهُوَ عَلَى كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ</item>
        <item>Sub-han Allah (33)
        Alhamdu lillah (33)
Allah hu Akbar (33)
Laa ilaaha ill-allaahu, waḥdahu laa shareeka lahu, lahul-mulku wa lahul-ḥamdu, wa huwa ‛alaa kulli shay’in qadeer (1)</item>
        <item>Glory is to Allah
Praises are due to Allah
Allah is the greatest
None has the right to be worshipped but Allah alone, He has no partner, His is the dominion and His is the praise and He is Able to do all things</item>
        <item>Whoever says this after every prayer will be forgiven his sins even though they be as the foam of the sea.  [Muslim no. 597] Muslim 1/418</item>
        <item>Recite first 3 duas 33 times each and last dua 1 time after every Fard Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 7</item>
        <item>لَا إِلٰهَ إِلَّا اللهُ وَحَدْهُ لَا شَرِيكَ لَهُ، لَهُ الْمُلْكُ وَلَهُ الْحَمْدُ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ، وَهُوَ عَلَى كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ</item>
        <item>Laa \'ilaaha \'illallaahu wahdahu laa shareeka lahu, lahul-mulku wa lahul-hamdu yuhyee wa yumeetu wa Huwa \'alaa kulli shay\'in Qadeer</item>
        <item>None has the right to be worshipped but Allah alone, Who has no partner. His is the dominion and His is the praise . He brings life and He causes death , and He is Able to do all things</item>
        <item>At-Tirmithi 5/515, Ahmad 4/227. See its checking in Ibn Al-Qayyim Al-Jawziyyah\'s Zadul-Ma\'ad 1/300</item>
        <item>Recite 10 times after Maghrib and Fajr Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 8</item>
        <item>ٱللَّهُ لَآ إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ ٱلْحَىُّ ٱلْقَيُّومُ ۚ لَا تَأْخُذُهُۥ سِنَةٌ وَلَا نَوْمٌ ۚ لَّهُۥ مَا فِى ٱلسَّمَٰوَٰتِ وَمَا فِى ٱلْأَرْضِ ۗ مَن ذَا ٱلَّذِى يَشْفَعُ عِندَهُۥٓ إِلَّا بِإِذْنِهِۦ ۚ يَعْلَمُ مَا بَيْنَ أَيْدِيهِمْ وَمَا خَلْفَهُمْ ۖ وَلَا يُحِيطُونَ بِشَىْءٍ مِّنْ عِلْمِهِۦٓ إِلَّا بِمَا شَآءَ ۚ وَسِعَ كُرْسِيُّهُ ٱلسَّمَٰوَٰتِ وَٱلْأَرْضَ ۖ وَلَا يَئُودُهُۥ حِفْظُهُمَا ۚ وَهُوَ ٱلْعَلِىُّ ٱلْعَظِيمُ</item>
        <item>Allaahu laa \'ilaaha \'illaa Huwal-Hayyul-Qayyoom, laa ta\'khuthuhu sinatun wa laa nawm, lahu maa fis-samaawaati wa maafil-\'ardh, man thal-lathee yashfa\'u \'indahu \'illaa bi\'ithnih, ya\'lamu maa bayna \'aydeehim wa maa khalfahum, wa laa yuheetoona bishay\'im-min \'ilmihi \'illaa bimaa shaa\'a, wasi\'a kursiyyuhus-samaawaati wal\'ardh, wa laa ya\'ooduhu hifdhuhumaa, wa Huwal-\'Aliyyul- \'Adheem</item>
        <item>Allah! There is none worthy of worship but He, the Ever Living, the One Who sustains and protects all that exists. Neither slumber nor sleep overtakes Him. To Him belongs whatever is in the heavens and whatever is on the earth. Who is he that can intercede with Him except with His Permission? He knows what happens to them in this world, and what will happen to them in the Hereafter. And they will never encompass anything of His Knowledge except that which He wills. His Throne extends over the heavens and the earth, and He feels no fatigue in guarding and preserving them. And He is the Most High, the Most Great</item>
        <item>al-Baqarah: Ayah(255), Whoever recites Aayatul Kursi after every Fard (Fard Salah), only death is keeping him/her from entering Jannah. (As soon as he/she dies, will enter Jannah) (Nasa’i, Ibne Hibban,Kanzul Ummal)  Al-Albani, Sahihul-Jami\' As-Saghir 5/339 and Silsilatul-Ahadith As-Sahihah 2/697 (no. 972)</item>
        <item>Recite Once after every Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 9</item>
        <item>بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ "قُلْ هُوَ اللهُ أَحَدٌ ۞ اللهُ الصَّمَدُ ۞ لَمْ يَلِدْ وَلَمْ يُولَدْ ۞ وَلَمْ يَكُن لَّهُ كُفُوًا أَحَدٌ</item>
        <item>Bismillaahir-Rahmaanir-Raheem. Qul Huwallaahu \'Ahad. Allaahus-Samad. Lam yalid wa lam yoolad. Wa lam yakun lahu kufuwan \'ahad</item>
        <item>With the Name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. Say, "He is Allah [who is] One, Allah, the Eternal Refuge, He neither begets nor is born, Nor is there to Him any equivalent</item>
        <item>Al-Ikhlas 112:1-4 Whoever recites (Three Qul) three times in the evening and in the morning will protect you against everything. Al-Albani\'s Sahih At-Tirmithi 3/182</item>
        <item>3 times after Fajr and Maghrib Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 10</item>
        <item>بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ "قُلْ أَعُوذُ بِرَبِّ الْفَلَقِ ۞ مِن شَرِّ مَا خَلَقَ ۞ وَمِن شَرِّ غَاسِقٍ إِذَا وَقَبَ ۞ وَمِن شَرِّ النَّفّٰثَٰتِ فِي الْعُقَدِ ۞ وَمِن شَرِّ حَاسِدٍ إِذَا حَسَدَ</item>
        <item>Bismillaahir-Rahmaanir-Raheem. Qul \'a\'oothu birabbil-falaq. Min sharri maa khalaq. Wa min sharri ghaasiqin \'ithaa waqab. Wa min sharrin-naffaathaati fil-\'uqad. Wa min sharri haasidin \'ithaa hasad</item>
        <item>With the Name of Allah, the Most Gracious, the Most Merciful. Say: I seek refuge with (Allah) the Lord of the daybreak, from the evil of what He has created, and from the evil of the darkening (night) as it comes with its darkness, and from the evil of those who practice witchcraft when they blow in the knots, and from the evil of the envier when he envies</item>
        <item>Al-Falaq 113:1-5  Whoever recites (Three Qul) three times in the evening and in the morning will protect you against everything. Al-Albani\'s Sahih At-Tirmithi 3/182</item>
        <item>3 times after Fajr and Maghrib Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 11</item>
        <item>بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمٰنِ الرَّحِيمِ "قُلْ أَعُوذُ بِرَبِّ النَّاسِ ۞ مَلِكِ النَّاسِ ۞ إِلَهِ النَّاسِ ۞ مِن شَرِّ الْوَسْوَاسِ الْخَنَّاسِ ۞ الَّذِي يُوَسْوِسُ فِي صُدُورِ النَّاسِ ۞ مِنَ الْجِنَّةِ وَالنَّاسِ</item>
        <item>Bismillaahir-Rahmaanir-Raheem . Qul \'a\'oothu birabbin-naas . Malikin-naas . \'Ilaahin-naas . Min sharril-waswaasil-khannaas. Allathee yuwaswisu fee sudoorin-naas. Minal-jinnati wannaas</item>
        <item>With the Name of Allah , the Most Gracious , the Most Merciful. Say: I seek refuge with (Allah) the Lord of mankind, the King of mankind , the God of mankind , from the evil of the whisperer who withdraws, who whispers in the breasts of mankind, of jinns and men</item>
        <item>An-Nas 114:1-6 Whoever recites (Three Qul) three times in the evening and in the morning will protect you against everything. Al-Albani\'s Sahih At-Tirmithi 3/182</item>
        <item>3 times after Fajr and Maghrib Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Dua After prayer 12</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّي أَسْأَلُكَ عِلْماً نَافِعاً، وَرِزْقاً طَيِّباً، وَعَمَلاً مُتَقَبَّلاً</item>
        <item>Allaahumma \'innee \'as\'aluka \'ilman naafi\'an, wa rizqan tayyiban, wa \'amalan mutaqabbalan</item>
        <item>O Allah, I ask You for knowledge that is of benefit , a good provision , and deeds that will be accepted</item>
        <item>Ibn Majah and others. See Al-Albani, Sahih Ibn Majah 1/152 and Majma\'uz-Zawd\'id 10/111</item>
        <item>3 times after Fajr and Maghrib Salah</item>
        <item>transition</item>

    </string-array>
</resources>