<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="m_e_Array">
        <!-- First item is name,2nd is arabic, 3rd is arabish, 4th is translation, 5th is reference, 6th is number of times said-->
        <item>Surah Ikhlas</item>
        <item>قُلۡ هُوَ ٱللَّهُ أَحَدٌ (١) ٱللَّهُ ٱلصَّمَدُ (٢) لَمۡ يَلِدۡ وَلَمۡ يُولَدۡ (٣) وَلَمۡ يَكُن لَّهُ ۥ ڪُفُوًا أَحَدٌ (٤)</item>
        <item>Qul huwal laahu ahad Allah hus-samad Lam yalid wa lam yoolad Wa lam yakul-lahu kufuwan ahad</item>
        <item>Say: He is Allah, the One and Only;
            Allah, the Eternal, Absolute;
            He begetteth not, nor is He begotten;
            And there is none like unto Him.</item>
        <item>Whoever recites (Three Qul) three times in the evening and in the morning will protect you against everything.[Narrated by al-Tirmidhi, al-Da’waat, 3499, Sunan al-Tirmidhi, no. 2829]</item>
        <item>3</item>

        <!-- After 1 dua is completed need a transition item -->
        <item>transition</item>

        <item>Surah Falaq</item>
        <item>قُلۡ أَعُوذُ بِرَبِّ ٱلۡفَلَقِ ( ١ )  مِن شَرِّ مَا خَلَقَ ( ٢ )  وَمِن شَرِّ غَاسِقٍ إِذَا وَقَبَ ( ٣ )  وَمِن شَرِّ ٱلنَّفَّـٰثَـٰتِ فِى ٱلۡعُقَدِ ( ٤ )  وَمِن شَرِّ حَاسِدٍ إِذَا حَسَدَ ( ٥ )</item>
        <item>Qul auzoo bi rabbil-falaq
                Min sharri ma khalaq
                Wa min sharri ghasiqin iza waqab
                Wa min sharrin-naffaa-saati fil uqad
                Wa min shar ri haasidin iza hasad</item>
        <item>Say: I seek refuge with the Lord of the Dawn
                From the mischief of created things;
                From the mischief of Darkness as it overspreads;
                From the mischief of those who practise secret arts;
                And from the mischief of the envious one as he practises envy.</item>
        <item>Whoever recites (Three Qul) three times in the evening and in the morning will protect you against everything.[Narrated by al-Tirmidhi, al-Da’waat, 3499, Sunan al-Tirmidhi, no. 2829]</item>
        <item>3</item>

        <item>transition</item>
        
         <item>Surah Nas</item>
        <item>قُلۡ أَعُوذُ بِرَبِّ ٱلنَّاسِ ( ١ )  مَلِكِ النَّاسِ ( ٢ )  إِلَـٰهِ ٱلنَّاسِ ( ٣ )  مِن شَرِّ ٱلۡوَسۡوَاسِ ٱلۡخَنَّاسِ ( ٤ )  ٱلَّذِى يُوَسۡوِسُ فِى صُدُورِ ٱلنَّاسِ ( ٥ )  مِنَ ٱلۡجِنَّةِ وَٱلنَّاسِ ( ٦ )  </item>
        <item>Qul a\'uzu birabbin naas
Malikin naas
Ilaahin naas
Min sharril was waasil khannaas
Al lazee yuwas wisu fee sudoorin naas
Minal jinnati wan naas</item>
        <item>Say: I seek refuge with the Lord and Cherisher of Mankind,
The King (or Ruler) of Mankind,
The Allah (for judge) of Mankind,-
From the mischief of the Whisperer (of Evil), who withdraws (after his whisper),-
(The same) who whispers into the hearts of Mankind,-
Among Jinns and among men.</item>
        <item>Whoever recites (Three Qul) three times in the evening and in the morning will protect you against everything.[Narrated by al-Tirmidhi, al-Da’waat, 3499, Sunan al-Tirmidhi, no. 2829]</item>
        <item>3</item>

        <item>transition</item>
        
 <item>Ayatul Kursi</item>
        <item> بِسۡمِ ٱللهِ ٱلرَّحۡمَـٰنِ ٱلرَّحِيمِ

اللَّهُ لاَ إِلَهَ إِلاَّ هُوَ الْحَيُّ الْقَيُّومُ لاَ تَأْخُذُهُ سِنَةٌ وَلاَ نَوْمٌ لَهُ مَا فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ وَمَا فِي الأَرْضِ مَنْ ذَا الَّذِي يَشْفَعُ عِنْدَهُ إِلاَّ بِإِذْنِهِ يَعْلَمُ مَا بَيْنَ أَيْدِيهِمْ وَمَا خَلْفَهُمْ وَلاَ يُحِيطُونَ بِشَيْءٍ مِنْ عِلْمِهِ إِلاَّ بِمَا شَاءَ وَسِعَ كُرْسِيُّهُ السَّمَاو ;َاتِ وَالأَرْضَ وَلاَ يَئُودُهُ حِفْظُهُمَا وَهُوَ الْعَلِيُّ الْعَظِيمُ ( ٥ )</item>
        <item>Allahu la ilaha illa Huwa, Al-Haiyul-Qaiyum La ta’khudhuhu sinatun wa la nawm, lahu ma fis-samawati wa ma fil-‘ard Man dhal-ladhi yashfa’u ‘indahu illa bi-idhnihi Ya’lamu ma baina aidihim wa ma khalfahum, wa la yuhituna bi shai’im-min ‘ilmihi illa bima sha’a Wasi’a kursiyuhus-samawati wal ard, wa la ya’uduhu hifdhuhuma Wa Huwal ‘Aliyul-Adheem</item>
        <item>In the name of Allah, the Beneficent, the Merciful. “Allah! There is no god but He – the Living, The Self-subsisting, Eternal. No slumber can seize Him Nor Sleep. His are all things In the heavens and on earth. Who is there can intercede In His presence except As he permitteth? He knoweth What (appeareth to His creatures As) Before or After or Behind them. Nor shall they encompass Aught of his knowledge Except as He willeth. His throne doth extend Over the heavens And on earth, and He feeleth No fatigue in guarding And preserving them, For He is the Most High. The Supreme (in glory)</item>
        <item>Abu Hurairah reports:
“Whenever you go to bed, recite “Ayat-al-Kursi”– ‘Allaahu laa ilaaha illaa huwal-Hayyul Qayyuum’ till you finish the whole verse. (If you do so), Allah will appoint a guard for you who will stay with you and no satan will come near you till morning. ”
(Bukhari Book #38, Hadith #505)

Abu Huraira reported that “Prophet Muhammad (Peace Be Upon Him) ordered me to guard the chairty revenue of Ramadan. Then somebody came to me and started stealing of the foodstuff. I caught him and said, “I will take you to Allah Apostle! “That person said (to Abu Huraira), “Please don’t take me to Allah’s Apostle and I will tell you a few words by which Allah will benefit you. When you go to your bed, recite Ayat-ul-Kursi, (2.255) for then there will be a guard from Allah who will protect you all night long, and Satan will not be able to come near you till dawn.” When the Prophet heard the story he said (to me), “He (who came to you at night) told you the truth although he is a liar, and it was Satan.” [Sahih Al-Bukhari]</item>
        <item>1</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>

 <item>Bismillaahil-lathee</item>
        <item>بِسْمِ اللَّهِ الَّذِي لَا يَضُرُّ مَعَ اسْمِهِ شَيْءٌ فِي الْأَرْضِ وَلَا فِي السَّمَاءِ وَهُوَ السَّمِيعُ الْعَلِيمُ
</item>
        <item>Bismillaahil-lathee laa yadhurru ma\'as-mihi shay\'un fil-\'ardhi wa laa fis-samaa\'i wa Huwas-Samee \'ul- \'Aleem</item>
        <item>We have made (started) the morning (and night) in whose Name nothing in the skies and the earth can harm and He is the All-hearing, the All-knowing</item>
        <item>Abu Hurairah said: The Messenger of Allah used to teach his Companions, saying: “When one of you reached the morning, then let him say: (At-Tirmidhi 3391)</item>
        <item>3</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Radheetu billaahi Rabban</item>
        <item>رَضِيتُ باللهِ رَبَّاً، وَبِالْإِسْلَامِ دِيناً، وَبِمُحَمَّدٍ صَلَى اللهُ عَلِيهِ وَسَلَّمَ نَبِيَّاً</item>
        <item>Radheetu billaahi Rabban, wa bil-\'Islaami deenan, wa bi-Muhammadin (sallallaahu \'alayhi wa sallama) Nabiyyan.</item>
        <item>I am pleased with Allah as my Lord, with Islam as my religion and with Muhammad (peace and blessings of Allah be upon him) as my Prophet</item>
        <item>"Allah has promised that anyone who says this three times every morning or evening will be pleased on the Day of Resurrection." Ahmad 4/ 337</item>
        <item>3</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allaahumma bika \'asbahnaa</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ بِكَ أَصْبَحْنَا، وَبِكَ أَمْسَيْنَا، وَبِكَ نَحْيَا، وَبِكَ نَمُوتُ وَإِلَيْكَ النُّشُورُ</item>
        <item>Allaahumma bika \'asbahnaa , wa bika \'amsaynaa, wa bika nahyaa, wa bika namootu wa \'ilaykan-nushoor</item>
        <item>O Allah, by You we enter the morning and by You we enter the evening, by You we live and and by You we die, and to You is our resurrection</item>
        <item>Abu Hurairah said: The Messenger of Allah used to teach his Companions, saying: “When one of you reached the morning, then let him say: (At-Tirmidhi 3391)</item>
        <item>1</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allaahumma \'Anta</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ أَنْتَ رَبِّي لَا إِلَهَ إِلاَّ أَنْتَ، خَلَقْتَنِي وَأَنَا عَبْدُكَ وَأَنَا عَلَى عَهْدِكَ وَوَعْدِكَ مَا اسْتَطَعْتُ، أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ شَرِّ مَا صَنَعْتُ أَبُوءُ لَكَ بِنِعْمَتِكَ عَلَيَّ، وَأَبُوءُ بِذَنْبِي فَاغْفِرْ لِي فَإِنَّهُ لاَ يَغْفِرُ الذُّنُوبَ إِلاَّ أَنْتَ</item>
        <item>Allaahumma \'Anta Rabbee laa \'ilaaha \'illaa \'Anta, khalaqtanee wa \'anaa \'abduka, wa \'anaa \'alaa \'ahdika wa wa\'dika mas-tata\'tu, \'a\'oothu bika min sharri maa sana\'tu, \'aboo\'u laka bini\'matika \'alayya, wa \'aboo\'u bithanbee faghfir lee fa\'innahu laa yaghfiruth-thunooba \'illaa \'Anta</item>
        <item>O Allah, You are my Lord, there is none worthy of worship but You. You created me and I am your slave. I keep Your covenant, and my pledge to You so far as I am able. I seek refuge in You from the evil of what I have done. I admit to Your blessings upon me, and I admit to my misdeeds. Forgive me, for there is none who may forgive sins but You</item>
        <item>The Prophet (S.A.W) said, Whoever says this during the day, believing in it with certainty, then dies on that day before evening comes, will be one of the people of Paradise, and whoever says it at night, believing in it with certainty, then dies on that night before morning comes, will be one of the people of Paradise.”(Bukhari: 7/150)</item>
        <item>1</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allaahumma maa \'asbaha</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ مَا أَصْبَحَ (أَمْسَى) بِي مِنْ نِعْمَةٍ أَوْ بِأَحَدٍ مِنْ خَلْقِكَ فَمِنْكَ وَحْدَكَ لاَ شَرِيكَ لَكَ، فَلَكَ الْحَمْدُ وَلَكَ الشُّكْرُ </item>
        <item>Allaahumma maa \'asbaha (\'amsaa) bee min ni\'matin \'aw bi\'ahadin min khalqika faminka wahdaka laa shareeka laka, falakal-hamdu wa lakash-shukru.</item>
        <item>O Allaah, what blessing I have received in this morning (evening) or any of Your creation, is from You alone, without any partner, so for You is all praise and unto You all thanks</item>
        <item>Whoever recites this in the morning, has completed his obligation to thank Allah for that day; and whoever says it in the evening, has completed his obligation for that night (Ibn As-Sunni (Hadith no. 41))</item>
        <item>1</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allaahumma \'aafinee</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ عَافِنِي فِي بَدَنِي، اللَّهُمَّ عَافِنِي فِي سَمْعِي، اللَّهُمَّ عَافِنِي فِي بَصَرِي، لاَ إِلَهَ إِلاَّ أَنْتَ، اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّي أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنَ الْكُفْرِ، وَالفَقْرِ، وَأَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ عَذَابِ القَبْرِ، لاَ إِلَهَ إِلاَّ أَنْتَ</item>
        <item>Allaahumma \'aafinee fee badanee, Allaahumma \'aafinee fee sam\'ee, Allaahumma \'aafinee fee basaree, laa \'ilaaha \'illaa \'Anta. Allaahumma \'innee \'a\'oothu bika minal-kufri, walfaqri, wa \'a\'oothu bika min \'athaabil-qabri, laa \'ilaaha \'illaa \'Anta.</item>
        <item>O Allah, make me healthy in my body. O Allah, preserve for me my hearing. O Allah, preserve for me my sight. There is none worthy of worship but You. O Allah, I seek refuge in You from disbelief and poverty and I seek refuge in You from the punishment of the grave. There is none worthy of worship but You</item>
        <item>Abu Dawud 4/324, Ahmad 5/42</item>
        <item>3</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Hasbiyallaahu laa</item>
        <item>حَسْبِيَ اللَّهُ لاَ إِلَهَ إِلاَّ هُوَ عَلَيهِ تَوَكَّلْتُ وَهُوَ رَبُّ الْعَرْشِ الْعَظِيمِ</item>
        <item>Hasbiyallaahu laa \'ilaaha \'illaa Huwa \'alayhi tawakkaltu wa Huwa Rabbul-\'Arshil-\'Adheem</item>
        <item>Allah is sufficient for me. There is none worthy of worship but Him. I have placed my trust in Him, He is Lord of the Majestic Throne</item>
        <item>Allah will grant whoever recites this Seven times in the morning or evening whatever he desires from this world or the next (Ibn As-Sunni (no. 71), Abu Dawud 4/321)</item>
        <item>7</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allaahumma \'innee \'asbahtu</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ إِنّيْ أَصْبَحْتُ (أَمْسَيْتُ) أُشْهِدُكَ، وَأُشْهِدُ حَمَلَةَ عَرْشِكَ، وَمَلاَئِكَتِكَ، وَجَمِيعَ خَلْقِكَ، أَنَّكَ أَنْتَ اللَّهُ لَا إِلَهَ إِلاَّ أَنْتَ وَحْدَكَ لاَ شَرِيكَ لَكَ، وَأَنَّ مُحَمَّدًا عَبْدُكَ وَرَسُولُكَ</item>
        <item>Allaahumma \'innee \'asbahtu (\'amsaytu) \'ush-hiduka wa \'ush-hidu hamalata \'arshika, wa malaa\'ikataka wajamee\'a khalqika, \'annaka \'Antallaahu laa \'ilaaha \'illaa \'Anta wahdaka laa shareeka laka, wa \'anna Muhammadan \'abduka wa Rasooluka</item>
        <item>O Allah, verily I have reached the morning (evening) and call on You, the bearers of Your throne, Your angels, and all of Your creation to witness that You are Allah, none has the right to be worshipped except You, alone, without any partner and that Muhammad is Your Servant and Messenger</item>
        <item>Abu Dawud 4/317, An-Nasa\'i, Ibn As-Sunni.</item>
        <item>4</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Yaa Hayyu yaa Qayyoomu</item>
        <item>يَا حَيُّ يَا قَيُّومُ بِرَحْمَتِكَ أَسْتَغِيثُ أَصْلِحْ لِي شَأْنِيَ كُلَّهُ وَلاَ تَكِلْنِي إِلَى نَفْسِي طَرْفَةَ عَيْنٍ</item>
        <item>Yaa Hayyu yaa Qayyoomu birahmatika \'astagheethu \'aslih lee sha\'nee kullahu wa laa takilnee \'ilaa nafsee tarfata \'aynin</item>
        <item>O Ever Living, O Self-Subsisting and Supporter of all, by Your mercy I seek assistance, rectify for me all of my affairs and do not leave me to myself, even for the blink of an eye</item>
        <item>Al-Hakim 1/545. He said it is Sahih, and Dhahabi supported it</item>
        <item>1</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allaahumma \'innee \'as\'aluka</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ إِنِّي أَسْأَلُكَ عِلْمًا نَافِعًا، وَرِزْقًا طَيِّبًا، وَعَمَلًا مُتَقَبَّلًا</item>
        <item>Allaahumma \'innee \'as\'aluka \'ilman naafi\'an, wa rizqan tayyiban, wa \'amalan mutaqabbalan.</item>
        <item>O Allah, I ask You for beneficial knowledge, goodly provision and acceptable deeds</item>
        <item>It was narrated from Umm Salamah that when the Prophet (ﷺ) performed the Subh (morning prayer), while he said the Salam, he would say: (SUNAN IBN MAJAH HADITH NO. 925)</item>
        <item>3</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>\'A\'oothu bikalimaatil</item>
        <item>أَعُوذُ بِكَلِمَاتِ اللَّهِ التَّامَّاتِ مِنْ شَرِّ مَا خَلَقَ</item>
        <item>\'A\'oothu bikalimaatil-laahit-taammaati min sharri maa khalaqa</item>
        <item>I take refuge in Allaah\'s perfect words from the evil He has created</item>
        <item>Whoever recites in the evening three times (dua) then not so much as a stinger (humah) will harm him that evening (at-Tirmidhee 3898)</item>
        <item>3</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Laa \'ilaaha \'illallaahu</item>
        <item>لَا إِلَهَ إِلاَّ اللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ لاَ شَرِيكَ لَهُ، لَهُ الْمُلْكُ وَلَهُ الْحَمْدُ، وَهُوَ عَلَى كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ</item>
        <item>Laa \'ilaaha \'illallaahu wahdahu laa shareeka lahu, lahul-mulku wa lahul-hamdu, wa Huwa \'alaa kulli shay\'in Qadeer</item>
        <item>None has the right to be worshipped but Allah alone, Who has no partner. His is the dominion and His is the praise and He is Able to do all things</item>
        <item>"1. Allah will write ten Hasanaat (rewards) for whoever recites this ten times in the morning, and forgive him ten misdeeds and give him the reward of freeing ten slaves and protect him from Satan. Whoever recites this ten times in the evening will get this same reward. An-Nasa\'i, \'Amalul-Yawm wal-Laylah (no. 24). Its chain of transmission is sound (Sahih). Albani 1/272. Abu Hurayrah «fe narrated that the Prophet said: ""Allah will write one hundred Hasanat for whoever says There is no God but Allah alone, He has no partner. To Allah is possession of everything, and to Him all praise is. He is Capable of all things\' ten times in the morning, and forgive him one hundred misdeeds. He will have the reward of freeing a slave and will be protected from Satan throughout the day unto dusk. Whoever says it in the evening will have the same reward."" Ahmad 8/704, 16/293. Its chain of transmission is good (Hasan), Ibn Baz, p. 44. 
               2. Whoever recites this in the morning, will have the reward of freeing a slave from the Children of Isma\'il. Ten Hasanaat (rewards) will be written for him, and he will be forgiven ten misdeeds, raised up ten degrees, and be protected from Satan until evening. Whoever says it in the evening will have the same reward until morning. Abu Dawud 4/319, 3/957, Ahmad 4/ 60, Ibn Majah 2/331, Ibn Al-Qayyim Zadul-Ma\'ad 2/388. Its chain of transmission is sound (Sahih). Al-Albani 1/270."</item>
        <item>100</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Subhaanallaahi</item>
        <item>سُبْحَانَ اللَّهِ وَبِحَمْدِهِ عَدَدَ خَلْقِهِ، وَرِضَا نَفْسِهِ، وَزِنَةَ عَرْشِهِ، وَمِدَادَ كَلِمَاتِهِ</item>
        <item>Subhaanallaahi wa bihamdihi, \'Adada khalqihi, wa ridhaa nafsihi, wa zinata \'arshihi wa midaada kalimaatihi</item>
        <item>How perfect Allaah is and I praise Him by the number of His creation and His pleasure, and by the weight of His throne, and the ink of His words</item>
        <item>The Mother of the Believers, Juwairiyah bint Al-Harith (RadhiAllahu \'anha) reported: The Prophet (sal-Allaahu \'alayhe wa sallam) came out from my apartment in the morning as I was busy in performing the dawn prayer. He came back in the forenoon and found me sitting there. The Prophet (sal-Allaahu \'alayhe wa sallam) said, "Are you still in the same position as I left you.\'\' I replied in the affirmative. Thereupon the Prophet ﷺ said, "I recited four words three times after I had left you. If these are to be weighed against all you have recited since morning, these will be heavier. " Say: (dua) (Sahih Muslim 2726 a, Book 48, Hadith 106)</item>
        <item>3</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allahumma salli</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ صَلِّ وَسَلَّمْ عَلَى نَبِيِّنَا مُحَمَّدٍ</item>
        <item>Allahumma salli wa sallam \'alaa nabiyyinaa Muhammad</item>
        <item>Oh Allah, we ask you for peace and blessings upon our prophet Muhammad</item>
        <item>The prophet (peace be upon him) said: "Who recites blessings upon me 10 times in the morning and 10 times in the evening will obtain my intercession on the Day of Resurrection." At-Tabrani reported this Hadith together with two chain of transmissions. One of them is reliable (Jayyid). See Haithami\'s Majma\' Az-Zawa\'id 10/120, and Al-Albani\'s Sahih At-Targhib Wat-Tarhib 1/273</item>
        <item>10</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Asbahnaa wa \'asbahal-mulku</item>
        <item>أَصْبَحْنَا وَأَصْبَحَ (أَمْسَيْنَا وَ أَمْسَىا) الْمُلْكُ لِلَّهِ، وَالْحَمْدُ لِلَّهِ، لاَ إِلَهَ إلاَّ اللَّهُ وَحْدَهُ لاَ شَرِيكَ لَهُ، لَهُ الْمُلْكُ وَلَهُ الْحَمْدُ وَهُوَ عَلَى كُلِّ شَيْءٍ قَدِيرٌ، رَبِّ أَسْأَلُكَ خَيْرَ مَا فِي هَذَا الْيَوْمِ (هَذِهِ اللَّيْلَةِ) وَخَيْرَ مَا بَعْدَهُ (بَعْدَهَا)، وَأَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ شَرِّ مَا فِي هَذَا الْيَوْمِ (هَذِهِ اللَّيْلَةِ) وَشَرِّ مَا بَعْدَهُ (بَعْدَهَا)، رَبِّ أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنَ الْكَسَلِ وَسُوءِ الْكِبَرِ، رَبِّ أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ عَذَابٍ فِي النَّارِ وَعَذَابٍ فِي الْقَبْرِ</item>
        <item>Asbahnaa wa \'asbahal-mulku (\'Amsaynaa wa\'amsal-mulku) lillaahi walhamdu lillaahi, laa \'ilaaha \'illallaahu wahdahu laa shareeka lahu, lahul-mulku wa lahul-hamdu wa Huwa \'alaa kulli shay\'in Qadeer. Rabbi \'as\'aluka khayra maa fee haathal-yawmi (haathihil-laylati) wa khayra maa ba\'dahu (ba\'daha) wa \'a\'oothu bika min sharri maa fee haathal-yawmi (haathihil-laylati) wa sharri maa ba\'dahu (ba\'daha), Rabbi \'a\'oothu bika minal-kasali, wa soo\'il-kibari, Rabbi \'a\'oothu bika min \'athaabin fin-naari wa \'athaabin fil-qabri.</item>
        <item>We have reached the morning (evening) and at this very time unto Allaah, belongs all sovereignty, and all praise is for Allaah. None has the right to be worshipped except Allaah, alone, without any partner, to Him belong all sovereignty and praise and He is over all things omnipotent. My Lord, I ask You for the good of this day (night) and the good of what follows it and I take refuge in You from the evil of this day (night) and the evil of what follows it. My Lord, I take refuge in You from laziness and senility. My Lord, I take refuge in You from torment in the Fire and punishment in the grave</item>
        <item>The Prophet (S.A.W) used to say this Dua in the evening (At-Tirmithi 2699, al-Daw’aat, 3390, Muslim 4/2088)</item>
        <item>1</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Subhaanallaahi</item>
        <item>سُبْحَانَ اللَّهِ وَبِحَمْدِهِ</item>
        <item>Subhaanallaahi wa bihamdihi</item>
        <item>Glory is to Allah and praise is to Him</item>
        <item>"Whoever recites this one hundred times in the morning and in the evening will not be surpassed on the Day of Resurrection by anyone having done better than this except for someone who had recited it more. " Al-Bukhari 4/2071 Whoever says (the above) a hundred times during the day, his sins are wiped away, even if they are like the foam of the sea.[Sahih al-Bukhari; #7:168, Sahih Muslim; #4:2071]</item>
        <item>100</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>
        
        <item>Allaahumma \'Aalimal-ghaybi</item>
        <item>اللَّهُمَّ عَالِمَ الْغَيْبِ وَالشَّهَادَةِ فَاطِرَ السَّماوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ، رَبَّ كُلِّ شَيْءٍ وَمَلِيكَهُ، أَشْهَدُ أَنْ لَا إِلَهَ إِلَّا أَنْتَ، أَعُوذُ بِكَ مِنْ شَرِّ نَفْسِي، وَمِنْ شَرِّ الشَّيْطَانِ وَشِرْكِهِ، وَأَنْ أَقْتَرِفَ عَلَى نَفْسِي سُوءاً، أَوْ أَجُرَّهُ إِلَى مُسْلِمٍ</item>
        <item>Allaahumma \'Aalimal-ghaybi wash-shahaadati faatiras-samaawaati wal\'ardhi, Rabba kulli shay\'in wa maleekahu, \'ash-hadu \'an laa \'ilaaha \'illaa \'Anta, \'a\'oothu bika min sharri nafsee, wa min sharrish-shaytaani wa shirkihi, wa \'an \'aqtarifa \'alaa nafsee soo\'an, \'aw \'ajurrahu \'ilaa Muslimin</item>
        <item>O Allah, Knower of the unseen and the evident , Maker of the heavens and the earth , Lord of everything and its Possessor , I bear witness that there is none worthy of worship but You . I seek refuge in You from the evil of my soul and from the evil of Satan and his helpers . (I seek refuge in You) from bringing evil upon my soul and from harming any Muslim</item>
        <item>The Prophet (S.A.W) taught one of his companions and he said: “Say this in the morning and in the evening, and when you go to your bed.” Thirmidi 3/142 AbuDawud</item>
        <item>1</item>
        
         <item>transition</item>        
        
    </string-array>
</resources>
